Guide to the Records of the Brooklyn Council for Social Planning BCMS.0039
Brooklyn Collection
- Related non-government agencies, 1937-1957 [bulk 1945-1957]; 1945-1957
  - Other related agencies, circa 1948-1957 [includes undated material]
    - Brooklyn Bureau of Social Service and Children's Aid Society (Box 42, Folder 29)
    - Brooklyn Business and Professional Negro Women's Club (Box 42, Folder 30)
    - Brooklyn Cancer Committee (Box 42, Folder 31)
    - Brooklyn Catholic Interracial Council (Box 42, Folder 32)
    - Brooklyn Chamber of Commerce (Box 42, Folder 33)
    - Brooklyn Child Guidance League (Box 42, Folder 34)
    - Brooklyn Civic Center (Box 42, Folder 35)
    - Brooklyn Children's Museum [Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences] (Box 42, Folder 36)
    - Brooklyn Civic Council (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Brooklyn Club (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Brooklyn Community Woodward School (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Brooklyn Concord Club (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Brooklyn Coordinating Committee for Fair Housing (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Brooklyn Council of Church Women (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Brooklyn Council for Social Planning (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn Diocesan Council of Catholic Women (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Brooklyn Dodgers (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Brooklyn Eye and Ear Hospita (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Brooklyn Federation of Mothers' Clubs (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Brooklyn Hebrew Home and Hospital for the Aged (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Brooklyn Hebrew Orphan Asylum (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Brooklyn Heights Press (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Brooklyn Hill Association (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Brooklyn Home for the Aged (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Brooklyn Home for Aged Colored People (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Brooklyn Home for the Aged Men (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Brooklyn Home for Children (Box 43, Folder 19)
    - Brooklyn Hospital (Box 43, Folder 20)
    - Brooklyn Human Relations Conference Newsletters (Box 43, Folder 21)
    - Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences (Box 43, Folder 22)
    - Brooklyn Interfaith Fellowship (Box 43, Folder 23)
    - Brooklyn Jewish Center (Box 43, Folder 24)
    - Brooklyn Jewish Community Council (Box 43, Folder 25)
    - Brooklyn Jewish Home for the Convalescents (Box 43, Folder 26)
    - Brooklyn Junior Chamber of Commerce (Box 43, Folder 27)
    - Brooklyn Juvenile Protective Agency: Brooklyn Child Guidance Center (Box 43, Folder 28)
    - Brooklyn Kindergarten Society (Box 43, Folder 29)
    - Brooklyn Lodge of Elks (Box 43, Folder 30)
    - Brooklyn Lamp Lighters Inc. (Box 43, Folder 31)
    - Brooklyn Museum [Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences] (Box 43, Folder 32)
    - Brooklyn Music School, The (Box 43, Folder 33)
    - Brooklyn Neighborhood Houses Fund (Box 43, Folder 34)
    - Brooklyn Neuro-Psychiatric Clinic (Box 43, Folder 35)
    - Brooklyn Psychiatric Society (Box 43, Folder 36)
    - Brooklyn Psychological Association (Box 43, Folder 37)
    - Brooklyn Society for Ethical Culture (Box 43, Folder 38)
    - Brooklyn Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Children (S.P.C.C.) (Box 43, Folder 39)
    - Brooklyn Sports Center (Box 43, Folder 40)
    - Brooklyn State Hospital (Box 43, Folder 41)
    - Brooklyn Thoracic Hospital (Box 43, Folder 42)
    - Brooklyn Tuberculoses and Health Association, Inc. (Box 43, Folder 43)
    - Brooklyn Veterans Administration Hospital (Box 43, Folder 44)
    - Brooklyn Veterans' Service Center (Box 43, Folder 45)
    - Brooklyn Women's Bar Association (Box 43, Folder 46)
    - Brooklyn Woman's Club (Box 43, Folder 47)
    - Brooklyn Women's Hospital (Box 43, Folder 48)
    - Brownsville Boys' Club [Boys' Clubs of America] (Box 43, Folder 49)
    - Business and professional women's clubs (Box 43, Folder 50)
    - C: Miscellaneous (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Caledonian Hospital (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Cancer care, National Cancer Foundation (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Camp Fire Girls (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Cathedral Club (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Catholic Charities (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Catholic Dentist Guild (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Catholic Guild for the Blind (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Catholic Seamen's Institute (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Catholic Youth Organization (C.Y.O.) (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Central Bureau for the Jewish Aged (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Cerebral Palsy, the Coordinating Council for, and United Cerebral Palsy (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Child Care Center Parents Association (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Child Study Association of America (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Children's Day and Night Shelter (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Children's Welfare League of Brooklyn (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Chiropean Club (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Church Mission of Help, Youth Consultation Service (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Church of the Open Door (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - Citizens' Budget Commission (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Citizens' Crime Committee of Greater NY (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - Citizens' Committee for Children of NYC: Report, "For Children in Trouble" (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - Citizens' Committee for Children of NYC: Analysis of NYC Dept. of Health Budgets, 1954- (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - Citizens' Committee for Children of NYC: General (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - Citizens' Housing and Planning Council of New York, Inc. (Box 44, Folder 25)
    - Citizens' Housing and Planning council of NY: Citizens' Housing News (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Citizens Union of the City of New York (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Civitas Club (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Club Ta-Wa-Ses (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Colony House (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Committee for Protection of Children in Downtown Brooklyn (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Community Consultation Center (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Community Councils of NYC (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Community Service Society of New York (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Concord Child Care Center (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Consumers League of New York (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Cooley's Anemia Blood and Research Foundation for Children (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Council of Jewish Organizations of Bensonhurst and Mapleton (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Council of Spanish-American Organizations of Greater New York (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Cumberland Hospital (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - D: Miscellaneous (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Deer Club (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Democratic State Committee (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Dental Society of Kings County (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Dodger Knot-Hole Club, Inc. (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Dr. White Memorial Catholic Settlement (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Dr. White Memorial Recreation Center (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Downtown Brooklyn Association (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Dyker Heights Nursery School for Blind Children (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - E: Miscellaneous (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - East Midwood Jewish Center (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - East New York Boys Club (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - Eighth Avenue Merchants and Civic Association (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - Eighty-Sixth Street Board of Trade (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - Emerald Association (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - Emmanuel Baptist Church, Emmanuel Christian Center (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - Esplanade Democratic Club (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - Evangelical Home for the Aged (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - F: Miscellaneous (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - Federation of Jewish Philanthropists (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, Inc. (Box 45, Folder 36)
    - Fifth Avenue Association (Box 45, Folder 37)
    - Fifth Avenue Bay Ridge Board of Trade (Box 45, Folder 38)
    - Flatbush Avenue Merchants Association (Box 45, Folder 39)
    - Flatbush Boys' Club (Box 45, Folder 40)
    - Flatbush Chamber of Commerce (Box 45, Folder 41)
    - Florence Hoberman Philanthropic League (Box 45, Folder 42)
    - Fordham University School of Social Service (Box 45, Folder 43)
    - Fort Greene District Civic Association (Box 45, Folder 44)
    - Free Nurses Institute (Box 45, Folder 45)
    - Foundation House (Box 45, Folder 46)
    - G: Miscellaneous (Box 45, Folder 47)
    - G.I. Pipe Smokers Club (Box 45, Folder 48)
    - Girl Scouts, Inc. (Box 45, Folder 49)
    - Girls Vacation Fund, Inc. (Box 45, Folder 50)
    - Glenwood Nursery School (Box 45, Folder 51)
    - Good Neighbor Civic League of Brooklyn (Box 45, Folder 52)
    - Goodwill Industries of Brooklyn (Box 45, Folder 53)
    - Graham Home for the Old Ladies (Box 45, Folder 54)
    - Grand Street Settlement (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Greater New York Council of Agencies for the Blind (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Greater New York Safety Council (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Group for Community Guidance Centers (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - H: Miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Haym Salomon Home for Aged (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Health Career Horizons (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Health Information Foundation (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Hebrew Educational Society (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Home for Aged and Infirm Hebrews of New York (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Homecrest Child Guidance Center (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Hospital Council of Greater New York: Bulletin (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Hospital Council of Greater New York: Reports (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - I: Miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Immaculate Conception Day Nursery (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Infants Home of Brooklyn (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Industrial Home for the Blind (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Italian Board of Guardians (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Italian Historical Society of America (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - J: Miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Jefferson Boys Club (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - Jacob Riis Community Center (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - Jewish Association for Neighborhood Centers (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - Jewish Board of Guardians (Box 46, Folder 24)
    - Jewish Community House of Bensonhurst (Box 46, Folder 25)
    - Jewish Hospital of Brooklyn (Box 46, Folder 26)
    - Jewish Sanitarium and Hospital for the Chronic Diseases (Box 46, Folder 27)
    - Jewish War Veterans, Kings County Council (Box 46, Folder 28)
    - Junior Achievement (Box 46, Folder 29)
    - Junior League of Brooklyn (Box 46, Folder 30)
    - K: Miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 31)
    - Kallman Home for Children (Box 46, Folder 32)
    - Kings County Hospital (Box 46, Folder 33)
    - Kings County Podiatry Society (Box 46, Folder 34)
    - Kingston Avenue Hospital: Geriatrics Rehabilitation Center (Box 46, Folder 35)
    - Kiwanis Club (Box 46, Folder 36)
    - Knights of Columbus (Box 46, Folder 37)
    - Kosmos Club (Box 46, Folder 38)
    - L: Miscellaneous (Box 46, Folder 39)
    - Labor Youth League (Box 46, Folder 40)
    - Lafayette Community Center (Box 46, Folder 41)
    - Lane Bryant Award (Box 46, Folder 42)
    - League for Emotionally Disturbed Children (Box 46, Folder 43)
    - League for Industrial Democracy (Box 46, Folder 44)
    - League of Women Voters (Box 46, Folder 45)
    - Legal Aid Society (Box 46, Folder 46)
    - Lions Club (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Lobell Memorial Building (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Long Island College Hospital and College of Medicine (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Long Island University (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Louis Solomon Benevolent Society (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Lutheran Inner Mission Society (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Lutheran Medical Center (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Lutheran Welfare Council (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - M: Miscellaneous (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Marine Park Civic Association (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Marriage Council of Brooklyn (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Masons (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Mayor's Committee on Unity (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Medical Society of the County of Kings and Academy of Medicine of Brooklyn (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Men's League of Brooklyn (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Menorah Day Center (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Menorah Home and Hospital for Aged and Infirm (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Methodist Hospital, Park Slope (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Metropolitan New York Association for Childhood Education (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Monsignor Kerby Guild of the Diocese of Brooklyn (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Montauk Club (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Motion Picture Council (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Municipal Club of Brooklyn (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Muscular Dystrophy Association (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - Myasthenia Gravis Foundation (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - N: Miscellaneous (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - National Association for Mental Health (Box 47, Folder 27)
    - National Association of Social Workers: General (Box 47, Folder 28)
    - National Association of Social Workers: Social Policy and Action Committee (Box 47, Folder 29)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) (Box 47, Folder 30)
    - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing (Box 47, Folder 31)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews (Box 47, Folder 32)
    - National Conference on Prevention and Control of Juvenile Delinquency (Box 47, Folder 33)
    - National Council of Jewish Women, Brooklyn Section (Box 47, Folder 34)
    - National Dairy Council (Box 47, Folder 35)
    - National Education Association of the United States (Box 47, Folder 36)
    - National Federation of Settlements (Box 47, Folder 37)
    - National Health Council (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - National Multiple Sclerosis Society, Kings County Chapter (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - National Publicity Council for Health and Welfare Services, Inc.: Publications (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - National Publicity Council for Health and Welfare Services, Inc: "Channels" [news bulletin], 1955, 1957 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - National Social Welfare Assembly, Inc. (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - National Tuberculosis Association (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - National Urban League for Social Service Among Negroes (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Nay Yard District Boys Club (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Needlework Build of America, Brooklyn Branch (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Neighborhood Council on Youth Problems (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - New Hope Guild Center of Adelphi College (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - New Star Boys Club (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - New York Adult Education Council, Inc. (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - New York City CIO Council, Community Services Committee: Correspondence and Pamphlets (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - New York City CIO Council, Community Services Institute, 1957 April 27 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - New York City CIO Council, NYC Trade Union Directory, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - New York City CIO Council, "Union Counsellor Manual", 1955 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - New York Heart Association (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - New York Jewish Child Care Council (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - New York School of Social Work, Columbia University (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - New York School of Social Work, Columbia University: Workshop, "The Stake of Social Work in Urban Renewal Developments", 1957 June (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - New York State Welfare Conference (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - New York Women's Trade Union League (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Norwegian Lutheran Deaconess Home and Hospital (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Norwegian Seamen's Church and Norwegian Seamen's House (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Nurse Association of the Counties of Long Island (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - National Desertion Bureau, Inc. (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - O: Miscellaneous (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Optimist Club of Brooklyn (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Ninad Club [9th Assembly District, Bay Ridge] (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Orphan Asylum Society of the City of Brooklyn, Brookwood Child Care (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Oral Hygiene Committee of Greater New York (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - P: Miscellaneous (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Parkway Community Council (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Planned Parenthood (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Play Schools Association (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Pratt Institute (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Protestant Council of the City of New York (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - Public Education Association (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Public Schools Athletic League, Girls' Branch (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - Puerto Rican Board of Guardians (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - R: Miscellaneous (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Rebecca Talbot Perkins Adoption Society (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Regional Plan Association (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Rhoda Schaap Council House [National Council of Jewish Women] (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Riverdale Children's Association (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Rotary Club of Brooklyn (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Rudder Club (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Rugby School, The (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - S: Miscellaneous (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - School Districts 25 and 27, Community Association of (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - School Districts 26 – 28: District Parents Workshop (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - School Districts 32, 33, and 34: Bushwick Schools Community League (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - St. Finbar's Religious Vacation Center (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - St. John's Episcopal Hospital (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - St. Vincent's Home for Boys (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Salvation Army, The (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Shorefront Jewish Community Center (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Society of St. Vincent de Paul (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Soroptimists Club (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - South Brooklyn Neighborhood Houses [formerly Little Italy Neighborhood Association] (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - State Charities Aid Association (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Sun-N-Fun Camp (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - T: Miscellaneous (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - U: Miscellaneous [empty folder] (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - United Neighborhood Houses (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - United Community Funds and Councils of America [formerly Community Chests and Councils of America]: General (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - United Community Funds and Councils of America: "Community" [bulletin] [incomplete], 1954-1957 (Box 50, Folder 27)
    - United Hospital Fund (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - United Housing Foundation (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - United Epilepsy Association (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - United Nations (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - United Parents Associations (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - U.S.O. [United Service Organization] (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - V: Miscellaneous (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Veterans of Foreign Wars, Brooklyn Council (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Visiting Nurse Association of Brooklyn (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Vocational Consulting Associates (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - W: Miscellaneous (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - W. Arthur Cunningham Civic Association (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Warren Street Community Center, Inc. (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Washington Heights Citizens Organize to Aid Youth (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Week for Blind (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Welcome Wagon, Inc. (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Welfare Council of New York City: Weekly Welfare Bulletin (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - William H. Hodson Community Center (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Williamsburg Kiwanis Club (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Williamsburg Settlement of the Brooklyn Philanthropic League (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Willoughby House Settlement (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Windsor Terrace Community Association (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Woman's Press (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - Women's American Organization for Rehabilitation through Training (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Women's Council for Civic Progress (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - World Politics: American Foundation for Political Education [Pratt Institute] (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - Wyckoff Heights Hospital (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - XYZ: Miscellaneous (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - Yeshiva University (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - YWCA Brooklyn (Box 51, Folder 30)
    - YMCA: Brooklyn and Queens (Box 51, Folder 31)
    - YMCA: Carlton Avenue (Box 51, Folder 32)
    - YM and YWHA of Boro Park (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - YM and YWHA of East New York (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - YM and YWHA of Williamsburg (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Young Adult Council (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Young Men's and Women's Organization for Rehabilitation through Training (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Youthbuilders (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Youth Counsel Bureau, NYC District Attorney's Offices, King County Unit (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Youth Service League (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Youth United for Better Citizens of Tomorrow: General (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Youth United for Better Citizens of Tomorrow: Press clippings (Box 52, Folder 10)
- Subject files, 1933-1957 [bulk 1950-1957]; 1950-1957
  Alphabetical by subject.
  Complementing the subject matter covered in the Program files (see Series 3), and overlapping somewhat with publications included in Series 6 and 7, this series is comprised of subject files on topics relating to the activities of BCSP. These files appear to have been used as reference materials by BCSP staff in planning their programs. Topics covered include: adoption, the aged, child care, child welfare, civil defense, court reform, day care, education, fluoridation of drinking water, health care, juvenile delinquency, summer camp, chronic illness, city planning, housing and health issues, housing discrimination, social welfare legislation, narcotics abuse (an extensive clipping file), Puerto Rican communities in New York City, and youth (including a large file of press clippings on gangs). Also included are files on Brooklyn history, and the Brooklyn Daily Eagle, as well as U.S. Census Bureau surveys and files of statistics on various social welfare topics.
  These files vary in size and comprehensiveness, and generally include press clippings, publications of various government and nonprofit organizations, articles from professional journals, directories, limited correspondence, and the occasional bibliography.
  - Accidents (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Adolescence (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Adoption (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Aged: Adult Education for Day Centers (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Aged: "Aging", Publication of the Department of Health, Education and Welfare (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Aged: General (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Aged: New York City: Report of the Mayor's Advisory Committee: Volume I and II (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Aged: New York City: Report of the Mayor's Advisory Committee: Volume III (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Aged: Press clippings (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Aged: New York State: Publications of the Joint Legislative Committee on Problems of the Aged (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Aged: New York State: Publications of the Joint Legislative Committee on Problems of the Aged (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Aged: New York State: Publications of the Joint Legislative Committee on Problems of the Aged (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Alcoholism (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Board Member Institute (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Brooklyn: Clippings: General (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Brooklyn: History [used in preparation of "Handbook for New Worker"] (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Brooklyn: History: New York Times articles, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Brooklyn: Pamphlets: General (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Brooklyn: Schools and Colleges (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn Eagle: Correspondence, 1950-1955 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Eagle: Press clippings (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn Eagle: 10-point program, 1952 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Brotherhood programs (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Camps: Day camps: Standards (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Camps: Overnight: Miscellaneous (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Catholic Church: "Metropolitan Catholic Telephone Guide", 1952 (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Census, U.S. Bureau of: Brooklyn Housing Census, 1950 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Census, U.S. Bureau of: Publications (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Child Care: Reference material (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Child Welfare (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Chronic Illness: General (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Chronic Illness, Commission on: Newsletter (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - City Planning: NYC City Planning Commission: Reports (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - City Planning: Plan for Rezoning of NYC, by Harrison Ballard and Allen, 1951 (Box 55, Folder 8)